and how do you think now, for example, uh,
а как вот ты считаешь сейчас например ээ
Russians, do they treat you in Russia as an
русские вам к вам в России относятся как
equal people or as some kind of
к равному народу или как к каким-то
savages? Well, the main population, of course,
дикарям Ну основное население конечно
how is this second-class because I also
как это второму сорту потому что я тоже
look Where, where, where, where, to us, this is the
смотрю Куда куда Да куда нам это
Orits they say that there are Russians, this is a
ориц они говорят что вот там русские это
real Great Nation, there is culture,
там прям Великая нация там культура
literature, and all the rest are naked bosses,
литература а все остальные голые боссы
how they ran there and some of their guts
как бегали там и какие-то из кишков
crawled out there, although 50 years
повылазили там хотя русские ещ 50 лет
ago the Russians themselves wore bast shoes in the
назад сами ходили в лаптях в
villages.
деревнях
Hello, where are you
Здравствуйте Вы
from,
откуда
Makhachkala? It's cool, and how do you communicate, Makhachkala,
Махач Прикольно а чём общаешься махакали
nets,
нец подр
what about both in a row? I
что обом подряд
understand. That's
Понял Вот
how you are, an Avar, a Dargin, kumy, a Lak, a
так ты аварец даргинец кумы лакец
Tabasaran, who are
табасаранец кто
you, a
ты
Tabasaran, I understand. My mother is a
табасаранец понял У меня мама
Dargin, yes, yes. And how are you there now, there is no
даргинка да да А как там у вас
war,
сечас войны
everything seems calm. I saw
нет вроде спокойно всё я видел
there, well, I saw something there, the formidable
там ну я видел там что-то грозные
bombed. Did you think that maybe Makhachkala too? Well,
бомбили ты думал может Махачкалу тоже
just even if it is not on such a
А да вот просто если даже будет не таки
scale, so that this somehow does not even
масштаба чтобы этот как-то даже не
notice you - that
заметь тебя-то
is, those who are
есть которые
fighting Yes, with this, most of my acquaintances are
воюют Да с этом большинство знакомых
male, young people of draft
мужской пол молодых призывного
age, 60-70 percent there are not How many
возраста процентов 60-70 там не Сколько
acquaintances do you have who died in the
у тебя знакомых есть которые погибли на
war, so
войне так
one, two, I
один
think two Well, there are
два по-моему
definitely two who have in common,
два Ну двое точно есть которых общее
common acquaintances, Tabasarans,
общие знакомы табасаранцы
yes, that is, they were brought there And so
да то есть их там привезли А так
acquaintances And so, according to the stories, there are a lot of
знакомых А так по рассказам очень много
bark And how does this happen, look, there are
коры А как так получается смотри там
Tabasarans, there are maybe 100 of you left there,
табасаранцы вас осталось там может там
100 a little more than 100,000 Yes, and you are being
100 100 чуть больше 100.000 Да и вас
sent to die for Russia
отправляют умирать за Россию
Well, like, how do you feel about the fact that you, a
Ну типа как ты относишься к тому что вас
small people, are being sent to die for the
маленький народ отправляют умереть за
Russian Empire
Империю российскую
Yes, you write down there, yes, or what,
Да там записываешь да или что
write down, it's scary This is
записывай страшно Это
the will What are they afraid of And what am I afraid of someone or something I do
воли Чего боятся А что кого-то боюсь что
n't know, many cowards in Russia Well, do
ли Не знаю многие трусы в России
n't confuse the truth Well, with a cautious
Ну ты не путай тру Ну ну осторожным
intellect, yes, naturally, when everything is
интеллектом да естественно когда всё
against you, there are no chances to somehow resist
против тебя шансов как-то противостоять
this Well, adequately And why take
этому Ну адекватно Да и зачем рисковать
unnecessary risks, that is, it's stupid Yes, if the
лишний раз то есть это глупо да если
force of the Rav could have been said, something I can
силу Рав можно было сказать чтото я могу
strain myself
напрягаться
that the recording will be  somewhere will get
что запись запись будет куда-то попадёт
then personal conversations personal witnesses
потом личные разговоры личные свидетели
why why right yes then how do you
зачем зачем правильно да то как вот ты
think Well why your guys of which there are
считаешь Ну зачем Ваши ребята которых и
so few left go to die in the
так мало осталось идут умирать на
war here just Yes that's how the situation got them
войну тут просто Да так ситуация у них
How the situation
попалась Как ситуация
got These people are not so small
попалась Это народ не так уж маленький
Well how
Ну как
small 150,000 Tabasarans
маленькие 150.000 табасаранцев
this is And you know 150,000 Tabasarans
это А ты знаешь 150.000 табасаранцев да
and 150,000 somewhere Russians in Dagestan
и 150.000 где-то русских Дагестане
why 150,000 Russians in Dagestan
почему 150.000 русских в
because they are occupiers in
Дагестане потому что они оккупанты в
Dagestan Well that's understandable but why there are so
Дагестане Ну это понятно но почему здесь
few here because their historical homeland is
мало потому что историческая родина ихня
where the Moscow swamp is
где болото московс
Well and Tabasarans that is there is a version that
Ну а табасаранцев то есть есть версия то
150 Tab and the historical homeland is nowhere
что 150 таба а исторический родих негде
I thought in
Я думал в
Dagestan Well I looked at the latest
Дагестане Ну я вот смотрел последние
research that exists that is they
исследования которые есть то есть они
say from Iran
говорят с Ирана
Don't look from Iran Tashi Tashi like in this in
Не смотри с Ирана таши таши типа в это в
Azerbaijan they are Iranian people Ossetians are a
Азербайджане они иранский народ осетины
foreign-speaking people Aran is not Iranian
иноязычный народ Аран же не Ирано
lingual well no not Iranian lingual but
язычный ну не не Ирано язычный но
some say it was in the 1st century when this one
некоторые говорят это в I веке когда вот
was Anu Shirvan he Tabaristan place
этот был ану ширван он табаристан место
from Dagestan Azerbaijan and further Here is this
из Дагестан Азербайджан и дальше Вот это
place This is Iran Tabaristan is called
место Это это Иран табаристан называется
that is they say this name also comes from
то есть они говорят это название тоже от
this But this is a version Well I look I
этого Но это версия Ну я вот смотрю я
look yes it says indigenous people of Southern
смотрю да написано коренной народ Южного
Dagestan indigenous who did not come I don’t
Дагестана коренной не пришедший
know they change very much that is this
не знаю они смены очень то есть это
Derbent place this is like a border used to be
Дербент место это как граница раньше
there this is all empires border
была там вот это всех империи граница
was there this is the passage Uz Trading
была там вот это проход уз Торговый
city was Yes this passage is narrow There
город был Да этот проход узкий Там
many are very displaced that is the people
многие это очень смещены то есть народ
there are Arabs Well I look yes that
там арабы Ну вот я смотрю да что
Tabasarans in language and culture are
табасаранцы по языку и по культуре к
closest to Lezgi for us
лезги нам ближе всего
yes Well yes in all close close Well
да Ну да на все
I just voiced this version
бли близ Ну просто я эту версию озвучил
which recently there genetics there they
которая вот недавно там генетика там
do all sorts of things they look there poet
всякие вещи делают же там смотрят поэтом
they attributed to Iran That is I just what I
они к Ираном отнесли То есть я просто то
read the latest
что читал последние
most I don’t know for the first time Yes such SZ from
самые не знаю я впервые Да такое СЖ из
Iranian in Dagestan and well more precisely so
иранских в Дагестане и ну точнее так вот
where Dagestan Azerbaijan from Iranian
там где Дагестан Азербайджан из иранских
It's only the Talosh there in Azerbaijan and in
Это только талоши там в Азербайджане и в
North and in Ossetia these as
северной и в Осетии эти как
they Iranians oh
они иранцы ой
Yes they are also a foreign-speaking people in look
Да они тоже иноязычный народ во смотри
for the whole history that the territory it is
за всю историю то что территория она
historically This is where we Tabasarans
исторически Вот это где мы табасаранцы
somewhere in Iran was why not Iran
где-то де Ирана было почему не не Иран
only for some time controlled this
только некоторое время контролировал эту
territory of Alexander
территорию Александра
the Great not Wait where time and
Македонского не Подожди где врем ещ
then this and these Mongols Muri by Nida
потом это и эти монголы мури бы ниды
in short Who was not there like Iran
короче Кто там только не был типа Иран
Iran only was a certain piece of
Иран только был определённый кусок
time not I read there the main Here who is the
времени не я там читаю основной Вот кто
biggest this even when this
самый большей это даже когда вот это
Arabs Islam this all Came this which is
арабы ислам вот это всё Пришёл вот это
there they fought with Iran against the
который там есть они с Ираном против
Arabs When then Iran lost
арабы воевали Когда потом Иран проиграл
then Islamization Went this all
потом исламизация Пошла вот это вот всё
[music]
[музыка]
here to Russia as they this And this
вот к России как они вот это И вот эта
territory went to Russia When there was a
территория к России отошли Когда была
war between Iran and Russia Iran lost And
война Иран между России Иран проиграл И
then Russia came there and Iran Well
потом Россия туда пришла и Иран Ну
thank them for betrayal they said
спасибо им за предательство они сказали
there everything We have no claims and then
там всё Мы претензий не имеем и потом
only if you are not in the know
только если ты не в курсе
Yeah interesting Yes really mountains Understand and how do
Угу интересно Да реально гор Поня а как
you think now for example uh
вот ты считаешь сейчас например ээ
Russians, do they treat you in Russia as an
русские вам к вам в России относятся как
equal people or as some kind of
к равному народу или как к каким-то
savages
дикарям
Well, the main population of course, how is this
Ну основное население конечно как это
second class because I also
второму сорту потому что я тоже
look and where do we need this
смотрю да куда нам это
orits they say that there are Russians there, there is a
ориц они говорят что вот там русские это
real Great Nation there, there is culture,
там прям Великая нация там культура
literature and all the rest are naked bosses,
литература а все остальные голые боссы
like they ran there and some savages
как бегали там и какие-то дикие из
crawled out of the villages there, although
кишлак повылазили там хотя русские ещё
50 years ago the Russians themselves wore bast shoes in the
50 лет назад сами ходили в лаптях в
village If you look at it like that Well,
деревне Если так посмотреть это
in essence, Russia When it was formed
Ну ну по сути Россия Когда образовалась
about recently, only how many 30-something years, is
о недавно только сколько 30 с чем-то лет
n't that 30 years When Yeltsin made
не это 30 лет Когда Ельцин сделал
ROSI them Wow, theirs and Peter I, where 300-
РОСИ их Вот это да их а Пётр I дагде 300
something years and that's it and before
С чем-то лет да и всё
that there were naked bosses running around there in their faces
там а до этого бегали там в лицах голые
in general
боссы вообще
Arn I know how Russian I speak I say
Арн Я знаеш как русски говорю говорю
what is the oldest city in this Russia
какой самый старый город этого России
they are starting there Novgorod I also say
они начинают там Новгород ещё я говорю
Hey Hello Hello I say you know what
Эй Алло Алло говорю ты знаешь что
Derbent How old are they like well I know But
дербенту Сколько лет они типа ну знаю Но
this is like this is not Russian  city ​​I
это же типа это не русский город я
say wait So you say the
говорю подожди Так ты говоришь самый
oldest city in Russia yes And they start to
старый город России да И они начинают
dodge because it turns out when
юлить потому что получается когда
Derbent was the greatest city it was a
Дербент был величайшим городом он ту
commercial and industrial city Well, there was a
торгово промышленный был город Ну
trade city and artisans and merchants there, it was
торговый там и ремесленники купцы
huge, like yes, it was at the
огромный был типа да он так на
intersection there, that's where the Silk Road was and
пересечении там это там Шёлковый путь и
so on Yes, in Moscow,
так дальше Да вот то в Москве вообще
toads were croaking, there was no one there yet yes
жабы квакали ещё там никого не было да
yes
да
yes an ancient city Well, I'm saying this it
да древний город Ну я же говорю этот это
turns out that it was the only passage
получается единственный проход был
From where you could go there further
Откуда можно было пройти там уже дальше
Neva there are mountains everywhere There is impassable only this is the
Нева там горы везде Там не проходимый
only one there, in
только это единственный такой там
my opinion, 2 or 3 km such a strip and that's
по-моему 2 или 3 км такая полоска и это
where, in my opinion, silk pu too From there too,
там по-моему шёлка пу тоже Оттуда тоже
what in my opinion yes yes all this is what you need
что по-моему да да всё вот это что надо
this I want to go I just haven't been there for a long time
это я хочу поехать Я просто давно не был
I'm Makhachka I think it's a fortress all this
там я махачка жи думаю это крепость всё
again to look at it this is
это ещё раз посмотреть это
really very UNESCO in my opinion Yes,
реально очень ЮНЕСКО по-моему Да
too, and Makhachkala By the way, it is named
тоже а Махачкала Кстати она называется в
after some communist Makhachka yes yes
честь какого-то коммуниста махача да да
yes yes
да да
Makhachkala is a city Kala Kale is a
Маха кала - это город кала кале - это
city Yes Makhachkala is  like Makhach is a
город Да Махачкала - это типа Махач
city so it turns out yes yes something it seems to
город так получается да да что-то это
me
по-моему
R
Р
Yes since in Crimea le like
Да так как в Крыму ле типа
yes it is a recent city Yes relatively there
да это недавно город Да относительно там
years just it is better bigger more
лет просто она получше побольше
interesting that is why here in general Well also
поинтереснее поэтому здесь вообще Ну
now they are building
сейчас строится
there But [ __ ] of course these
там А вот сри коне эти
roads yes because of the heat How is it
дорогу да из-за жары Как так получается
that Russia is so rich has oil gas
что Россия такая богатая имеет нефть газ
diamonds but can not make
алмазы а не может людям сделать
electricity for people so that it is
электричество чтобы было
uninterrupted that is also the
бесперебойное то есть тоже
area And so here what is what is I will
района А так здесь что есть что есть
say I myself have not encountered Here everything is
скажу я сам не сталкивался Здесь всё
normal Well relatively on go govo
нормально Ну относительно на го гово
some basic things there is electricity there well I would
какие-то базовые вещи есть там свет там
not recommend this city to anyone
ну этот город никому не рекомендовал бы
of course
конечно
how And what yes
как А что да
yes say yes a unique city yes And what is
да скаже да своеобразный город да А что
wrong in
не так в
Makhachkala It seems to me everything is wrong here
Махачкале Мне кажется здесь всё не так
Well for example that they will beat them up they will rob
Ну например что там побьют ограбят
no they will not rob the city itself is such a city Well they do
не не ограбят сам по себе такой город Да
not develop troubles let's say so Why is the
ну не развивают бед скажем так Почему
main city of Dagestan why is it
самый главный город Дагестана почему его
not
не
developed I know this is a question and you also
развивают Я знаю это вопрос и ты тоже
know we just will not voice it
знаешь просто озвучивать не будем
so that Yes so that this like an oak tree or there is a load
чтоб Да чтоб этот как дуба или там груз
there certain things are needed  to do
там определённые вещи нужно сделать
in order to do it Well yes yes and then and then now
чтобы это сделать Ну да да а то а то
maybe talk and then Yes now
сейчас может наговорить а потом Да
now they will knock with someone not
сейчас сейчас постучатся с кто-то не
now they will knock and then they will knock on the
сейчас постучатся а потом постучатся по
skull
черепко
yes yes yes yes what about I understood this and in Moscow I
да да да да что про понял это а в Москве
was Damn I wanted this passport in the summer I was sweating
был Блин я летом хотел этот паспорт
damn Well and in general have you ever been to
потел блин Ну а вообще был когда-то в
Moscow or not Well I never had a special desire
Москве или нет Ну у меня особого желание
so yes I'm interested
никогда не было так вот да мне интересно
I ask many Russians
я у многих россиян спрашиваю вот
look there we are in Ukraine every
смотрите там мы в Украине каждый
Ukrainian has essentially been to Kyiv at
украинец по сути был в Киеве хоть хотя
least once yes a lot of times and people in Russia in
бы раз да кучу раз а люди в России во
many regions have never even
многих регионах в Москве даже никогда не
been to Moscow Moscow is something so distant
были Москва - это что-то такое далёкое
and alien it turns out yes Well yes yes yes
и чуждое получается да
this well it considers two
Ну дада да этот ну это считает два
different Worlds Moscow And
разных Мира Москва И
there one Russian tells me that
там мне один россиянин говорит что
Moscow is not Russia Moscow is
Москва - это не Россия Москва - это
separate
отдельная
there essentially and in terms of standard of living in terms of
там по сути да и по уровню жизни по
mentality there in terms of salaries these are two
менталитету там по зарплатам это две
different
разные
things this is St. Petersburg and Moscow and if you stay That is it
вещи это Питер и Москва и если оста То
turns out Moscow, or
есть получается Москва
rather all of Russia feeds
она точнее вся Россия кормит
Moscow knows how Well it turns out from all the
Москву знает как Ну получается у всех
regions Take oil gas diamonds
регионов Забирать там нефть газ алмазы
there timber  coal gold everything everything-everything
там древесину уголь золото всё всё-всё
yes and Moscow what is it it does not
да а Москва что там она она же ни нефти
produce oil or gas anything
не добывает ни газа ничего
Yes look I really looked at America
Да смотри я вот реально смотрел Америку
there the situation is like this USA approximately
там ситуация такая вот США примерно
plus or minus states all the same there is
плюс-минус штаты все одинаковые
no such thing what are there some
такого нету что есть там какие-то
obvious differences there you can do any everything is
отличия там явные ты можешь любой всё
normal there any city you can go
там нормально любой город можешь поехать
any there more or less And here such
любой там более-менее А здесь такие
differences center everything And there behind the rest
перепады центр всё А там за за остальным
already some because Moscow Moscow
уже какая-то потому что Москва Москва
it perceives all these territories as
она воспринимает все эти территории как
its colonies yes that is Moscow it
колонии свои да то есть Москва она
historically as it was yes the Imperial center
исторически как было да Имперский центр
it robbed the colonies and took people from there
он грабил колонии и вывозил оттуда людей
resources money That's the same thing is
ресурсы деньги Вот то же самое и сейчас
happening now and that's why the colonies are poor Yes
происходит и поэтому колонии бедные Да
if you look at Dagestan You
вот если посмотреть Дагестан У вас же
produce gas there Gas Oil Well what
там газ добывает Газ Нефть
I know is that there
Да ну я то что я знаю то что газнефть
is gasneft but the volumes that is the question well I will
есть но объёмы этот вопрос то есть ну я
say this if if nearby Azerbaijan
скажу так если если рядом Азербайджан
also has a sea shelf Yes Azerbaijan
также имеет шельф моря Да Азербайджан
produces so much that it even sells
добывает столько что продаёт даже за
abroad and Dagestan supposedly produces Yes and it
границу и Дагестан типа добывает Да и
can produce but it turns out that it lives
может добывать а получается что жит
poorly what is poorer than the Moscow region
бедно че беднее чем Московская область
which has no gas most
которая никаких газа не
likely one of the poorest regions in
всего один из самых бедных регионов в
Russia most
России скоре
likely not
всего не
here
са вот
wanted a blogger studying Ukraine
хотел блогер изучаю украи
here you know Shpak from Russia
вот Шпака знаешь из России
and Alexander
а Александр
Shpak you don't know him I don't
Шпак это не знаешь его не
know or don't know or don't want I don't know I don't
знаю или не знаешь или не хочешь не знаю
know Yes there is one blogger
не знаю не знаю Да там есть один блогер
in short from Russia he left after the stench
короче с России он этот уехал после вони
like he's drowning in Ukraine said he has
типа за Украине топит сказал у него там
relatives there Ukrainians there the USA left
родственники есть украинцы там США уехал
there only for this against Russia there
там только так за этот против России там
understood you
понял
know purely for Ukraine Well you in Russia
знае чисто за Украину Ну заты в Росси
maybe Ukraine I don't know and you are a
может Украина не знаю а ты
Muslim Yes
мусульманин Да
of course And in what other Muslim
конечно А в каких ещё мусульманских
countries have I
странах
been
был
Muslim I would never go anywhere further than
я мусульманских я я вообще бы дальше
Dagestani cities even to
дагестанских городов нигде не бы даже в
Turkey to Azerbaijan it
Турцию в Азербайджан не ездил
turns out
получается вот
further I ate there a hundred Damn so Azerbaijan
дальше ел там ста Блин так Азербайджан
it's just a damn drive I don't
это же у вас просто блин проехать Не
know 100 kilometers and Azerbaijan will be there
знаю километров 100 и Азербайджан будет
yes Azerbaijan is there I don't know what to
да Азербайджан там я не знаю мне там что
do there I went further This is
туда ехать я Дальше поехал Вот это
Turkey This is Saudi Arabia I
Турция Вот это Саудовская Аравия туда
want to go there this is Dubai Azerbaijan I wouldn't want well
хочу вот это Дубай Азербайджан не хотел
to Dubai Everyone wants Yes everyone wants to
бы ну в Дубай Все хотят Да все хотят
see what's there
посмотреть что там
Dubai says smallpox I have a passport  Lost really
Дубай гово оспо Я паспорт Потер реально
wanted to go to Moscow lost passport I do
в Москву хотел поехать паспорт потерял Я
n't know Was at sea and because of this damn
не знаю На море был и из-за этого блин
this passport now need to make a passport with I
этот паспорт сейчас надо паспорт с
understand Yes it's interesting And listen, but
делать понял Да интересно А слушай а вот
you had a story when in Dagestan
у вас было когда история что в Дагестане
at the airport like a ray they were looking for and there
в аэропорту типа рее искали а там вот
this uh flew around everything that the guy Just
это ээ облетело всё что пацан Просто
looked into the turbine Yes and they made a picture
смотрел в турбину Да а сделали картинку
that he was like looking in the turbine
что он типа ищет в турбине
remember not he hardly said Yes I think
помнишь не он вряд ли сказал Да я думаю
I check on And you know the joke what a joke Here
я чек на А знаешь прикол прикол какой
here Yes well some guys there
Вот вот здесь Да ну пацаны некоторых там
support Palestine there
поддерживают там палестину там
guys suffered you know probably yes that
пострадали ребята ты в курсе наверное да
they were given a kick in the ass given a ski And I
то что им срака дали ски дали по А я
just saw a video in short there is one who is a
сейчас виде видел короче там один кто
blogger from
блогер есть из
Dagestan that is and he is filming there in
Дагестана то есть и он там снимает в
Dubai and it turns out they
Дубае и там оказывается
met there Here people are fighting for them there
встретились Здесь люди за них там гается
doing something there And it turns out there will
там что-то делат А там оказывается там
show a guy one from Palestine
покажет пацана один с Палестины
and another from Israel that is they are walking there
а другой с Израиля то есть ходят там
doing it it turns out your guys in Dagestan
делат получается ваши пацаны в Дагестане
held a protest action got sentences for it
делали акцию протеста получили за это
in support of Palestine And in  In Dubai, the
сроки в поддержку Палестины А в Дубае
Palestinians and the Israelis are all calm and
палестинцы с израильтянами все спокойно
normal.
нормально
Yes, I was
Да меня
also surprised why the guys
тоже меня тоже так удивляло зачем пацаны
from Dagestan are alive, Muslims in Russia, and
из Дагестана жива мусульман в России да
they are really oppressed there. And for the
которых там ущемляют реально А за
Palestinians, somewhere there, for them, even
палестинцев где-то там за них даже ну
if they don’t even stand up for them, even the
если за них не вписываются даже там
neighboring Arab countries of Egypt and Jordan,
соседние арабские страны Египет Иордания
for example, yes, then you should, like,
там например да то то что вы должны типа
worry about them at all.
вообще за них переживать что-то Там они
They’ll figure it all out there, they don’t give a damn about you,
все разберутся они плевать на вас хотели
like, well, that’s essentially how it turns out. Yes, life is
типа ну по сути так получается да жизнь
such an unfair thing, that
так несправедливая штука то
is, when you look, you see, when
есть тоже когда смотришь Видишь там
Muslims are here, everything is needed there,
когда вот мусульмане попа нужно там всё
but it turns out that’s how it is.
а оказывается Вот оно
I also m, when I always
как такая жез Мне тоже м я всегда когда
met people from the Caucasus, like, they were there
встречал типа людей из Кавказа они там
for Palestine, I say, Listen,
что-то за палестину Я говорю Слушай
wait, these Palestinians don’t give a
подожди этим палестинцам на вас вообще
damn about you, they don’t even know about you, the
плевать они даже не знают про вас
existence of your Dagestan, and they
существование вашего Дагестана и они
think that some kind of wild people
думают это какие-то там дикие народы
live there. Yes, and you’re
живут Да А вы там
worried there, guys, they got sentences for this
переживаете пацаны сроки получили за эту
action at the airport, damn. Yes, now, yes, yes, yes,
акцию аэропорту блин Да теперь да да да
Well, I’m sure that, well, maybe they
да Ну я уверен то что ну ну может они
even know but most don't even know
даже знают но большинство даже не знает
about us that is Arabs in fact they themselves
о нас то есть арабы по сути они сами
brought here and there and everything everything they
сюда и тамм принесли и всё всё они
consider themselves
считают себя
you they consider themselves above these
вы они себя считают выше эти
words Yes I heard this one there
слы Да я слышал вот этот одного там
Saudi Arabia there are their not he said
Саудовской Аравии есть их не он говорил
like we are Muslims here there Saudi sra the
типа мы здесь мусульмане там сауда сра
rest are second class like something like
остальные это второй сорт типа что-то
that I
такое
heard I don't even know what about the fact that they
слышал Я даже не знаю что о то что нас
know us that we exist there it's
знают то что мы существуем там это
somewhere you know like some kind of wild
где-то знаешь как типа какие-то дикие
distant peoples like for them
далёкие народы типа для них
Well I looked This Saudi
Да ну я смотрел Вот этот Саудовской
Arabia is little known but Turkey They
Аравии мало знают но Турция Вот это
know this I heard about not good Oso well without fanaticism
знают Я слышал о не хорошо Осо ну бе
Yes without fanaticism I understand the
фанатизма Да без фанатизма Я так понимаю
reality of this cruel world Yes I also
реали этого жестокого мира Да я тоже
supported Palestine
поддержал палестину
within the framework of reason there I understood what was
в рамках разумного там понимал что к
what
чему
there I just watch how the oppression of Muslims is going on in Russia
там просто я смотрю как в России идёт
for example when
Утес нение мусульман например когда
Russians build churches there in the Caucasus
русские делают там церкви на Кавказе Это
They consider this normal but when Muslims
они считают нормально а когда мусульмани
want to build a mosque there in Moscow in St. Petersburg in
хотят там в Москве в Питере в
Yekaterinburg
Екатеринбурге построить мечеть да сразу
some kind of protest immediately begins there that
начинается там типа какой-то протест что
migrants have arrived there And so on Well
там понаехали мигранты И так дальше Да
Yes that's why I'm telling you here Moscow has
ну Да поэтому я же тут говорю Москве
no particular desire  I had some
особо желания не было у меня какого-то
there and then I am now Why did I just go
там и то я сейчас Почему поехал просто
there it turns out my father He went say Come I say
там у меня отец получается Он поехал
Okay I'll come and have
говори Приезжай говорю Ладно приеду
a look Although I live in Moscow in Russia I have
посмотрю Хоть в Москве жив в России
never seen Moscow there ho for the
Москве не видел там хо для интереса хо
sake of interest ho I'll have a look I never wanted to If you can only go here abroad somewhere from you it turns out ots ret vba less to fly than to Moscow in my opinion Yes there in general there you need to go somewhere there 1000 something kilometers there well for the sake of interest now I'll measure it on the map
там ну ради интереса сейчас я по карте
And I Let's argue I bet on Dubai Dubai is
А я Давай спорим Я ставлю на Дубай Дубай
closer It also seems to me that
ближе Мне тоже кажется что Дубай ближе
Dubai is closer yes I also think that Dubai is
да я себе тоже считаю что Дубай
closer but now we will definitely find out on the map
ближе но сейчас мы точно по карте узнаем
so so so
так
Dubai
так так Дубай
op so from Dubai to Makhachkala
оп так от Дубая до Махачкалы
km
км
sweat yes And now
пот да А сейчас
we'll see to Moscow
посмотрим до Москвы
to Moscow 1500 no to Moscow a little
до Москвы 1500 нет до Москвы чуть-чуть
less 500 km less
меньше на 500 км меньше
Yes essentially
Да по сути
fly
лететь
Yes they
Да
screwed up so
прокололись так
I see that Dubai is generally
что я я смотрю что Дубай вообще у людей
very popular among people from the Caucasus  Dubai Yes yes
с Кавказа Очень популярный Дубай Да да
this is generally considered by you like it's
это вообще это у вас считается типа там
cool to visit Dubai yes to live
это типа круто побывать в Дубае да жить
in
в
Dubai it's cool to live in general to move in general
Дубае жить круто вообще переехать вообще
if possible I would immediately move to
если если возможно сразу переехал бы на
hakal in general And I have many acquaintances living in
хакала вобще А много знакомых живут в
Dubai Yes
Дубае у меня
acquaintances Just there are people who
Да знакомые Просто есть люди которые
come and go there
есть которые приезжают уезжают такие
are And what do they do for a living, what do they
есть А кем они работают что они кем они
do for a living, that they have money to live in
работают что они имеют деньги жить в
Dubai
Дубае
and here this acquaintance is this Yago I've
а вот тут этот знакомый есть этот Яго
known for a long time they are builders That is,
знаю давно они это строители То есть у
they have construction businesses
них строительны бизнеса
there yes they build houses and there they also have
там да дома строят и там у них тоже есть
houses there an apartment they have there well basically
там дома квартира есть у них там ну осно
these officials leave from there there a
оттуда уезжают вот эти чиновники там
businessman good money
бизнесмен хорошие деньги
who let's say how to say
кото это скажем как сказать
Yes who has money yes And so who does
Да у кого бабки есть да А так у кого
n't there What to do there such an
нету там Что там делать там такой
expensive city There it's better to go to Maha Poda
дорогой город Там лучше Маха пода
there
поехать там
GTO so you know there is such a selection Whoever got ahead from a
ГТО так знаеш тут такой отбор Кто из
small town somewhere
маленького Городка где-то выбился
moves to Makhachkala Whoever
переезжает в Махачкалу Кто в Махачкале
rose up somewhere in Makhachkala moves to Dubai Yes
где-то поднялся переезжает в Дубай Да
that's how it is
вот так
Dato a lot of
Дато много
blo pom also
бло пому тоже
there well that's different  level Yes another
туда ну это другой уровень Да другой
stage of life Well it's natural it's one
этап жизни Ну это естественно это один
of the best cities in the world it's considered a
из самых лучших городов в мире считается
flood Dubai is a very safe city
потопом Дубай это безопасный город очень
for Muslims who consider religion as at
для мусульман кто религию это считай как
home that is here not as not at
у себя дома то есть здесь не как не у
home roughly speaking yes haka And there as at
себя дома грубо говоря да хака А там как
home Everything is familiar there the
у себя дома Всё всё привычно там
culture is all similar As they say
культура всё там схожее Как говорится
as at home the climate there Well at least only in the summer
как у себя дома климат там Ну хоть летом
Well as they say if there were big
Ну как говорится имелись бы большие
bucks very big but for example
бабки очень большие а вот например у вас
in Dagestan I see it's very popular here
в Дагестане я смотрю очень популярно вот
e M Yes
э M Да
MMA like
MMA типа
fights you need to do but I'm not so special Well I
бои надо заниматься но я так особо Ну
did it myself but I know Yes what is it
сам занимался это но знаю Да что это
This show Yes it's just purely for the
такое Это шоу Да это просто чисто для
bucks yes they'll earn
бабок да заработают
anyway it's one of the ways to
по-любому это один из способов
earn bucks That is if Well it's
заработать бабки То есть если Ну это
few people achieve there well I it's the same
мало кто добивается там ну я это так же
as in football Yes a lot of people play and
как в футболе Да играет куча народу а
only a few get bucks
получает бабки только несколько
yes Well yes as there too you know what kind of
да Ну да как там тоже там знаешь какая
crazy competition there is also depends on luck there
бешеная конкуренция там от везения тоже
such competition here
зависит там там такая конкуренция здесь
every second one does there while
там каждый второй занимается там пока
this is pawned then will pawn Well yes as luck would have it that one
это заложи то заложит Ну да как повез
somewhere collarbone  accidentally broke
тому где-то ключицу случайно поломалось
and the Armed Forces and careers Further there are many cases
и ВС и карьеры Дальше нету много случаев
there are who it is not so fell not so
есть кто это не так упал не так
twisted everything broke Well you
подвернул там всё сломалось Ну бабки
can have money if you
можно если ты грамотно
sign up correctly Well it depends on your
подписаться Ну это кому как
luck Well you know who is famous
повезёт Ну вот это знаеш кто знамениты
they are in the same area
они в одном районе
Khabib You probably all watch Khabib
Хабиба У вас наверное все смотрят Хабиба
Well I basically already yes like that
Да ну я уже в основном да как этот там
on TV I don’t really watch anything there is a
по телевизору особо ничего не смотрю там
series there are all sorts of just yes Like on dosu let’s
сериал там всякие просто да Как на досу
say entertainment without
скажем развлечени без
fanaticism in Russia I see in many
фанатизма в России я смотрю во многих
cities such a Russian community has become these are
городах сделалась такая русская община
Russian nationalists walking and there is
это русские националисты ходят и там
like a patrol do you have such a
типа патруль у вас там есть такой
Makhachkala there or they don’t stick their noses in And here no here not
Махачкале или они не суются А здесь нету
here very much in percentage
здесь не здесь очень пов процентном
ratio Russian at least little that is
соотношении русский хоче мало то есть
3% of the total population Yes Yes I even
там 3% от всего населения Да Да Даже
say 150,000 but that’s from TH with something
говорю 150.000 но это от ТХ с чем-то
million that is
миллионов то
Very few and among themselves here are the
есть Очень мало а между собой вот
Dagestanis what language do they
дагестанцы на каком языке на аварском
speak Avar or
говорят или на
Russian Earlier, as far as I
русском Раньше у нас насколько мне
know, in my opinion
известно по-моему
before the arrival of Russia
до прихода России у
we had Avar that’s like  military was that is
нас аварский это как войсковой был то
when something happened Well, in
есть когда что-нибудь случалось
general we had Arabic Kumyk
А ну обще у нас арабский был кумыкский
Kumyk yes yes for the fact that it was easy there and
кумыкский да да за то что он лёгкий там
Arabic two languages ​​Yeah Well
был и и арабский два х языка Угу Ну
Arabic was like this church can Oh
арабский был как это церковный можно Ой
not church like religious Yes
не церковный как бы религиозный Да
religious Akum for about
религиозный акумы для об
too AC
тоже АС
I also studied Arabic It's just that something with
Я тоже изучал арабский Просто что-то у
my teacher ul did not study it to the end I
меня с учителем ул не до конца изучил Я
also studied Arabic you
тоже арабский
write No I could read read just
пишешь Не я мог читать читать просто
read then I had
читаю потом у меня
this conflict with the teacher after I did
это конфликт вышел с учителем после его
not see him conflict you
не видел конфликт ты там двоечку ему
gave him a bad grade there conflict with the
зарядил конфликт с
teacher VKT
учителем ВКТ
Yes specifics of the region Yes this is a common
Да специфику региона Да это у нас частое
occurrence with us and for me my studies were
явление и у меня что-то обучение
interrupted Well now it means something is needed
прервалось Ну сечас значи надо что-то
Yeah Well ideal for a Muslim of course
Угу Ну идеаль для мусульманина конечно
So Arabic this is necessary a petition
Значит арабский этот надо прошение там
there like somehow common for
туда типа как-то общий такой для
Muslims Yes
мусульман Да
Like yes yes we have our own language you know the
Типа да да у нас у нас свой язык знаешь
early language there are half Arabic words
ранский язык там половина арабские слова
that is
то есть
they know how much they had there
они знаю сколько у них там были там
Russia is 150 years old and with them with the Arabs there
России 150 лет а с ними с арабами там
600 500 700 years in their composition the Armed
600 500 700 лет уних составе
Forces are postponed their
откладывается ВС их
training culture there in the language Everything is
обучение культура там в языке Всё
half Arabic
половина арабские
words and you have such guys that like
сло а у вас есть такие пацаны что типа
went to fight in Syria once because
поехали воевать в Сирию когда-то потому
many from
много из
Russia against Assad I know that in Syria they
Росси против асада я знаю что в Сирии
even persecuted such guys like
там даже преследовали таких пацанов типа
But
Но
many Yes Here even this damn it was
много Дада Здесь даже вот это блин на
impossible to go out on the street there the beard is
улице невозможно было выйти там борода
not like that there even this acquaintance from the
не такая там под даже вот это знакомый с
mountains came he was detained there like what are you
гор приехал его там задержали типа ты
Syria or something going to Syria there yes
что Сирий что ли в Сирию едешь там да
many went who here there was a desire Here
многие ехали кто вот желание было Вот
this at one time I went even when this
это одно время идил даже когда вот это
was I don’t even know yes yes
было не знаю
I am here Yes to people Yes
Я здесь Да людям Да
here we will say Yes you seem to be at home and not at
здесь скажем Да ты вроде бы дома и не
home this is the situation here And what do
дома вот такая ситуация здесь А чем в
people mainly earn what in
основном люди зарабатывают чем в
Dagestan people
Дагестане люди
earn
зарабатывают
earn the main thing
зарабатывают основной
that the army went Policeman and military man that’s what the
что армию поехал Полицейский и военный
main thing is only for the
вот что основно то есть только на
state yes security officer yes
государство да силовиком да
Yes and the rest what do they
Да а остальные кем
work as taxis here taxis many
работают такси здесь такси много сфера
service sector here restaurants cafes Well this is a
обслуживания здесь рестораны кафе Ну это
big Makhakali you can  there is a delivery man there
больши махакали можно там доставщик там
in the store there well you can find if you
в магазине там ну можно найти если ты
want it's simple yes that's the
хочешь это просто да кото
main thing is that the city here you can wish for
основно так город здесь можно желать
this some million people here is
этот какой-то миллион человек здесь
such a millionaire yes a city of a million
такой миллионник да город миллионник
Makhachkala
Махачкала
Well yes alo What is the name of the agglomeration
Ну да ало Как называется агломерация
agglomeration yes yes Well they already there I think
агломерация да да Ну они уже там считаю
it's the same city because they are
это один и тот же город потому что они
already expanding expanding and still don't
уже расширяются расширяются и всё не
write the population uh Well yes the population is 600
пишут население э А ну да население 600
people yes and the agglomeration Million Well like I
человек да а агломерация Миллион Ну типа
got it with these Yeah
с этими понял
This is a million here just here very
Угу Это миллион здесь просто здесь очень
already everything a million city a millionaire
уже всё миллионный городно миллионник
should be rich Yes and people live
должен быть богатым Да а люди живут
poorly Well yes and the youth youth Where do they
бедно Ну это да а молодёжь молодёжь Куда
go well basically yes the
уезжает ну в основном да
youth Who somewhere someone to Moscow
молодёжь Кто куда то кто-то в Москву
someone to
кто-то в
America we have a lot
Америку у нас многое есть
which
которые
America Listen where will they
Америку Слушай
go where Well mainly Moscow
а куда пойдут куда Ну в основном Москву
yes well most of them there in Russia there in
да ну большинство туда в России там в
Moscow Soon there will be more Muslims than
Москве Скоро мусульман будет больше чем
Russians Well I somehow doubt there are
русских Ну я что-то сомневаюсь там
Russians how many 90% there no no there for a long time
русских сколько 90% там не не там давно
already there are not 90 not much more not 90 Listen but
уже их не 90 уже намного не 90 Слушай а
how many do you have  Dagestanis
вот сколько вот у вас у дагестанцев
How many children do they have now all the
Сколько сейчас детей все
children well usually there were a lot before this before this
детей ну обычно раньше много было это
now who already one two
раньше вот это сейчас кто уже оди два
maximum ceiling
максимум потолок
three and this this which nogo there se this is
три а это это который ного там се это
already an exception to the rule I think well there is of
уже исключение из правил считаю ну есть
course but basically it's
конечно но в основном это
2T yayu
2Т яю
somehow Maybe the numbers are understated or
както Может занижены цифры или что
something when they say about a Dagestani there
что-то когда про дагестанце говорят там
3 200 or something suspicious Of course and
3 200 или что-то подозрительно Конечно а
as you say like that
как вот ты говоришь типа что в Америку
young people even go to America and how do you feel about America
молодёжь даже едет а как вы к Америке
like America Yasha This is one of the
типа Америка Яша Это один из самых
coolest
классных
in general well it won't show the country itself in general in the
вообще ну не провит сама страна вообще в
world well probably one of the most Probably
мире ну наверное один из самых Наверное
if not the most and what is it the most
если не самый а чем она
it is a country that was created for
самая это страна которая создавалась для
free people it is for freedom
свободных людей это для свободы
initially itself for people who do not
изначально само для людей которые не
want to move somewhere and just
куда-то хотят переехать и просто
live freely It was originally a country of
свободно жить Это изначально это страна
immigrants yes like from old Europe
иммигрантов да типа из старой Европы
like which was monarchical there
типа которая была там монархическая
Yes all who moved there who it is like
Да все туда переехавшие кото она така
These are
Эти
even freedom Yes one of which I
даже свобода Да одна из которых Мне
like there Well not exactly freedom Well
нравится там Ну не прямо свобода Ну
some kind of Freedom there is there whatever you want to
какая-то Свобода там есть там что хочешь
do there even weapons are allowed if
делать там там даже о оружие разрешено
you want Do that is  and what do you think about the
хочеш Делай то есть а как ты считаешь
fact that Trump came and
что вот то что сейчас Трамп пришёл и там
he makes all sorts of wonderful
у него всякие такие дивные всякие
statements does he correspond to the spirit of this
заявления он соответствует духу вот этой
free America or is he some kind of weirdo it
свободной Америки или он какой-то чудик
turns out he is rather a weirdo he is something what
получается ну он скорее чудик он что-то
he does
то что он делает
somehow Well no one did that there I didn't either yes
как-то Ну никто такого не делал там я
now everyone even Americans are so
тоже да сейчас все даже американцы такие
dumbfounded that such a thing is happening Yeah well
офигеваю что такое типа происходит Да ну
some kind of I don't know what he hasn't saved up
ну какие-то там я не знаю что не накопил
or what he has there it seems to me you know
у него или что у него там кажется мне
he is there he is 78 years old
мне кажется знаешь ему там ему 78 лет
Putin is also over 70 for all these grandfathers
Путину тоже за 70 за этих всех дедушек
Yes we shouldn't allow
Да не надо допускать к власти нужно
some kind of youth or middle
чтобы какие-то молодёжь или средний
age to come to power Yes I have a friend
возраст был Да вот у меня знакомый есть
who told a businessman that is their
который говорил бизнесмену то есть их
elders he is 70 years old that is yes
там старши ему 70 Лет то есть да
man Yes
человека Да
mosi yes it seems that there are things that didn't happen that there are
моси да то мерещится то что не было то
obvious mental problems That is a
что психика явное проблемы То есть
person comes up with some kind of fantasy he
человек какие-то фантастику придумывает
says there are obvious
говорит вот это там явные какие-то уже
mental breakdowns that is real talk that is
перебои психики то есть реально гово то
such a thing is
есть такой
needed there Well 60 is the ceiling that is
ла там нужно Ну 60 - это потолок то есть
already everything is not allowed because  what So you
уже всё нельзя уже потому что Так
look yes everyone grew up everyone saw examples there
смотришь да все росли все видели примеры
in the yard somewhere there on the street there
там вот во дворе где-то там на улице
was always some old man who was already
всегда был какой-то дед которому там уже
over 70 years old and he already
за 70 с чем-то лет и у него уже он
started telling some fairy tales about the
начинал какие-то сказки рассказывать про
Germans there about astronauts something to him Yes to
немцев там про космонавтов что-то ему Да
invent
придумывать
Yes there already on the highway there I'll tell you there they
Да там уже по трасе там я тебе скажу там
generally bring this this is generally still here in
вообще заносят это это вообще ещё вот
America I'll tell you
Америке скажу
finances itself all the money there America the
финансы само одно все бабки там Америки
seal itself is the world currency that is that
сама печата это мировая валюта то есть
there you know how even Any person that
та там знаешь как даже Любой человек то
is for any Even the most janitor he
есть на какой-либо Даже самый дворник он
can just take a Ferrari
может себе просто взять Ferrari
loan for himself so you understand this really exists
кредит чтобы ты понимал это реально есть
which guy went He works as a delivery man an
который поехал парень Он доставщиком
ordinary delivery man took a good one This is a
работает обычный доставщик взял хороший
sports daughter Here which is here there
Вот это спортивный доч Вот который здесь
somewhere in the area of ​​there 40-30 000
там где-то в районе там 40-30 000
dollars cost a loan took everything there will be
долларов стои кредит взял всё там будет
everything
всё
Yes there even if they look at what they
Да там даже если посмотрят то что они
rent out look at their
сдают та посмотри како у них
infrastructure Generally a different level
инфраструктура Вообще другой уровень
If you compare them there for that kind of money
Если сравнивать их там за такие деньги
you can rent such a pethouse
там такие можно таких петхауз снимать
there in general this well to me I like you
там вообще это ну мне Мне нравится
know  when Russians say Well,
знаешь когда русские говорят Ну
objectively, if I look at the standard of
объективно вот если я посмотрю уровень
living in Ukraine, there in Europe and in America
жизни в Украине там в Европе и в Америке
Of course, I will say that the standard of living is lower in Ukraine
Конечно скажу что в Украине ниже уровень
Yes, but when Russians say
жизни Да вот но когда россияне говорят
that in America the salaries are high, but
что а в Америке большие зарплаты но
what is their
какая у них
Kona in X Zayani in two-story houses VM does
Кона в Х Зай анит в двухэтажных домах ВМ
not
не
refuse This is one of the highest standards of
отка Это один из самых высоких уровне
living in the world in general, yes, that is, I think the
жизни вообще в мире да то есть я считаю
West is the
вообще Запад
most, as I will say if we are people Yes, everything
самы как я скажу если мы люди Да все
among us is the most developed, this is
среди нас самое вот это развито вот это
how
вот как ра
developed That is, this is, this is, this
развиты То есть это есть это факт то
is, France Germany That is, look, they are
есть Франция Германия то есть посмотри
they are behind the wheel now in the world Well, you see,
они они за рулём сейчас в мире Ну видишь
now Trump wants to now Trump wants to
сейчас Трамп хочет сейчас Трамп хочет
pull the steering wheel towards himself very hard, he already
руль на себя дёрнуть очень сильно он уже
wants to push Europe aside Yes, and he
типа хочет Европу отодвинуть Да и
says that I am the king of the world here, like well, in
говорит что я тут король мира типа ну по
fact, yes, these are the Americans, the same
сути да это американцы те же самые
Europeans, that is,
европейцы то
this is just a hodgepodge of this
есть это там этот просто солянка этот
French, Germans, Germans, Irish,
французов там германцев немцев ирландцев
British
британцев
Well, what is there is, these are the Europeans, they are
Да ну то что есть есть это европейцы
at the moment They are the
это они на данный момент Они среди
best among humanity and the most
человечество самое лучшее и самое более
tolerable, they could come up with this at the
сносно это они смогли придумать на
moment That is, for now  nobody
данный момент То есть пока никто не
can with
может с
them really objectively yes that is if
ними правда объективно да то есть если
we look
мы смотрим
civilization once also was for example
цивилизация когда-то также была например
here is the civilization of Babylon there Ancient
вот цивилизация Вавилона там Древней
Greece Yes Ancient Rome Yes now
Греции Да Древнего Рима Да сейчас
European civilization Yes it is
европейская цивилизация Да она в
basically the driver as if all
принципе есть драйвером как бы всех
changes
изменений
scientific scientific and technological Revolution
науковой научно-технической Революции
If we look all there electricity
Если мы смотрим все там электричество
there is a steam engine all this all was
там паровой двигатель всё это всё было
invented like European civilization
придумано типа европейская цивилизации
over there the last 200-300 years Yes
за там последние там 200-300 лет Да
also Oh something your
тоже Ой что-то у тебя
phone all switched He
телефон всё переключился Он интересный
was an interesting conversation with Tabasaransev
разговор с табасаранцев был
yes write in the comments What do you
да напишите в комментариях Что вы
think about this conversation quite he so
думаете о этом разговоре довольно он так
honestly said something right away more precisely that he is
честно говорил кое-что сразу точнее что
afraid says he will not answer Come on and
боится говорит не будет отвечать Давай и
like subscribe comment and drop this video we
лайк подписка комент и скиньте це видео
know Glory to Ukraine write to y Telegram
знамо Слава украини пись на й Telegram
right now axis VN and
прям зараз ось ВН а
pok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg ORV in your ban and very  I
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
don't show a lot of videos to people sometimes I don't
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams That's why
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we Mali operational links are
того щоб мы Мали оперативный звязок
written right now And
пишиться прямо зараз А по
there in telegram we'll find videos that are also
там в телеграми окрим видео ще теж
interesting and useful information and we'll oblige
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
you to keep constant operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
links
звязок
independently in order to show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
write a
пиши а